As somebody who very much wants to believe that our beloved Mansoor is safe in Chesa, when he posted a video yesterday, I was, like so many of us, relieved to see that even though he seemed different, that he was alive.
I also saw a lot of people questioning the merit and the validity of the video.
And, you know, I'm not a conspiracy theorist, so it takes a lot for me to consider like the possibility of things like that, even in a world that is becoming much more AI driven than I feel like I would like to accept.
That said, I am always on a curiosity quest for truth.
And so I went and really studied the video.
As somebody who uses green screen a lot, which is what a lot of people were saying they feel like we were watching, I started to use just the knowledge I have about green screen to really examine the footage.
And I noticed something that is alarming to me.
So when you're keying out an image for green screen, essentially what you're doing is taking the background out of the image and putting another background behind it.
And in doing so, sometimes the image ends up having to be a bit more translucent so that it doesn't look like it's a 2D scenario, so that the person does look like they are immersed in the background.
In doing so, the translucency of the image can sometimes give way because if there are moving objects behind that image, it will show through because the image has been made translucent to try to help look more immersed in the green screen image.
What you're looking at, what you're looking at, what you're looking at, what you're looking at here is a car driving behind Mansour, but you're able to see through his image and notice the shadow of the car.
That would not be possible if his physical body was there.
I hope I am wrong.
I would love anything to be wrong.
After today's post, which was not a physical video and was only a voice note that sounded alarmingly like AI, which I am very sensitive to voices and to accents and to the nuances and many others are as well and have voiced that.
I think we must contend with the reality that we actually have not seen a safe Mansour and we do not know where he is and how he can be brought to safety.